rdg.ac.uk 2019-12-07

# Privacy policy and cookies information – University of Reading

### about us

This Privacy Notice explains the nature of the personal information that the University collects through our websites, when you provide your details to us at events or via online enquiry forms, from publically available sources, or via third parties that have passed us you contact details as you have expressed an interest in hearing from us. It also explains how your data is used and informs you of your rights under data protection laws.

The University and the Henley Business School are Data Controller ( **We or Us** ) in respect of the information that We process about you.  Our contact details are The University of Reading University of Reading, Whiteknights, PO Box 217, Reading, Berkshire, RG6 6AH, United Kingdom. Tel: +44 (0) 118 987 5123.

Your privacy is important to Us, so if there is anything in this privacy notice that is unclear or you do not understand, please contact Our Data Protection Officer at: [imps@reading.ac.uk](mailto:imps@reading.ac.uk)

### Data we collect about you

We operate a number of different websites and pages that support and enhance engagement with Us and our services, both for the benefit of students and other visitors. Some of those websites or webpages may be specific to a certain department, subsidiary or specific activities conducted across Our campuses- and may have additional information about how they collect and use personal data for their specific purposes. We encourage you to read those carefully in addition to this more general notice.

## Information that We collect directly from you 

We ask you for a range of personal information when you complete our online forms or applications for specific purposes: We collect personal data in order to:

\- Communicate with you about events and activities at the University

\- Provide you with information you have requested

\- To provide you with services, to managing bookings, and administer event requirements 

\- To tailor our communications to you 

\- To manage our websites and troubleshoot any problems

\- To track the effectiveness of our websites and monitor how users interact with them

We will collect information about you if you place an order with Us for a product or service, such as a prospectus, booking a place at a conference or event, subscribing to a newsletter or when you make an enquiry

## Information that we collect from other sources

We may receive contact details from third parties or agencies working for us where you have indicated that you would like to hear from Us. We may also collect personal data from publically available sources such as Companies House, LinkedIn or your Organisational websites. Where We do this We will notify you of the source of your personal data when We contact you wherever possible.

## Automatic Data Collection

We collect personal information about website (s) usage through cookies (see the section on Cookies, Google Analytics and third party cookies below) and server logs, which track the IP addresses of users visiting our site and the pages they visit.

Information collected via the University's server logs includes users' IP addresses and the web pages visited; this will be used to manage the web system and troubleshoot problems. 

The University also uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google") to understand how visitors engage with our website and so We can improve it. See the section on Google Analytics below.

### Cookies

Cookies are text files placed on your computer to help us analyse how users use our site. A cookie is a small data file able to track the online movements of an individual. This information could potentially be used to build an online profile of individuals and uniquely locate them in the world.

We use different types of cookies. Some are essential or necessary for the functioning or security of our websites, some analytics cookies are used to help Us to measure the performance of our websites and some are used by Us and third parties to deliver targeted advertising and marketing across other sites that you visit or interact with.

## Essential/Necessary/Functional Cookies

An example of these cookies are those that allocate your 'session ID'. This allows our server to recognise your computer and 'remember' what you've done on the site. The benefits of this are:

You only need to log in once if you're navigating secure areas of the site 

You are able to use interactive elements of the site, such as forms 

Our server can distinguish between your computer and other users, so you can see the information that you have requested.

## Performance/Analytics Cookies

An example of these cookies is Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to help us to understand how you make use of our content and work out how we can make things better. These cookies follow your progress through our website, collecting data on where you have come from, which pages you visit, and how long you spend on the site. This data is then stored by Google in order to create reports. These cookies do not store your personal data.

The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website, including your IP address, may be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google may use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for us and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. 

The Google website contains further information about Analytics and a copy of Google's privacy policy pages.

Other parts of the University's website also store cookies on your computer to track user traffic patterns. We do this to see how the website is used, to determine page popularity, to help security and for general statistical purposes. Some of this information may be held on servers in locations outside the EEA. Where personally identifying information is involved, data will only be held in locations that are deemed to have adequate protections for personal data.

## Marketing/Advertising/Third Party Cookies

Some cookies are dropped by parties external to the University, such as social media platforms. These enable the sharing of content via these channels and can also be used to track your interactions with sites visited and use this information to display targeted advertising and marketing to you.

For further information on cookies, including how you can see what cookies have been set and control cookies within your browser visit www.allaboutcookies.org or www.aboutcookies.org.

If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our website, you can set your browser to refuse cookies that are stored on your computer; the above websites tell you how to do this. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use or navigate through most parts of our website, although some functionality may be lost.

The following table gives details of the different types of cookies that might be used during a session.

## Necessary/Essential/Functional Cookies

 Cookie name |  Purpose  
---|---  
  
ROUTEID

.cms1

.cms2 | This is given to a user on the first request to a CMS server via the load balancer; it is required to ensure that subsequent request are always forwarded to the same frontend CMS server to maintain sessions.  
  
Cookiebar

CookieMessageShown

Test_cookie

| This cookie is used to determine if the user has accepted or declined cookies or whether your browser supports cookies  
  
ASPSESSIONID

ASP.NET_SessionID

ASP.NET cookie

Session ID

| 

These cookies automatically set and help perform essential functions and some interactive features of the University website such as online forms or to remember your login. It is only put on your computer when you use one of these features.  
  
 mysite#lang |  Stores the current site language. Used when switching the site content to a different language.  
 qtrans_front_language |  Stores the current site language  
  
PHPSESSID

| Used to generate session ID's and enable navigation of some sites, in particular our blog sites  
HENLEY_CSRF_TOKEN  | This cookie protects against forgery of form on our website and is required for the functioning of form submissions  
  
_hjClosedSurveyInvites 

_hjDonePolls

_hjMinimizedPolls

_hjDoneTestersWidgets

_hjMinimizedTestersWidgets

_hjIncludedInSample

_hjShownFeedbackMessage | These cookies perform necessary functions that prevent duplication of survey invites, polls you have already completed and widget minimisation and ensure your feedback is loaded and minimised on subsequent pages  
  
SnapABugVisit

SnapABugHistory

SnapABugRef | These cookies are necessary for the functionality of some of our livechat software to identify new user sessions, remember your session history, and identify your landing page and where you have navigated from.  
  
## Performance/Analytics cookies

Cookie Name | Purpose  
---|---  
  
_ga

_gid

_dc_gtm_ (prefix)

_gcl_au

_gat

| We use Google Analytics to help us to understand how you make use of our content and work out how we can make things better. These cookies follow your progress through our website, collecting data on where you have come from, which pages you visit, and how long you spend on the site. This data is then stored by Google in order to create reports. These cookies do not store your personal data.  
 nmstat |  This cookie is used to help record visitors' use of the website. This information is then used to improve the user experience on the website. The cookie contains no personal information and is used only for web analytics.  
  
SC_ANALYTICS_GLOBAL_COOKIE

SC_ANALYTICS_GLOBAL_SESSION_COOKIE

Siteimproveses (third party)

_cfduid (third party)

| These site improve cookies track repeated visits, sequencing of requests and pages viewed  
  
_Utma to _utmz

uvc | These cookies are set when you visit pages that allow share via social media links  
  
Wordpress

_author

_author_email

_author_url |  We use the WordPress platform for our blogs. When you comment on a blog post, WordPress will put some cookies on your machine that record the information you type in when you leave your comment. This means that you don't have to retype your details if you want to leave another comment.  
 _hjIncludedInSample | This cookie is used for user journey analytics on our Henley Business School sites  
  
Giosg_chat_id_{$COMPANY_ID}

Giosg_gid_{$COMPANY_ID}

Giosg_gsessid_{$COMPANY_ID}

| These cookies are used to distinguish unique users and determine new sessions and visits, to allow chat to continue from page to page and domain to domain in the case of shared rooms and for analytics  
 Hotjar 

_hjClosedSurveyInvites

_hjDonePolls

_hjMinimizedPolls

_hjDoneTestersWidgets

_hjIncludedInSample

_hjShownFeedbackMessage

_hjid

| 

We use Hotjar, an analytics and feedback tool, to improve the usability of our site. Hotjar sets persistent cookies (up to 365 days) for analytics purposes and to display the correct content to our visitors. You can read about what cookies are stored by visiting [_Hotjar's website_](http://docs.hotjar.com/docs/hotjar-cookies). 

Hotjar also records visitor information including mouse clicks and movements, scrolling activity and user input on our website (for example on the search box) - this information is anonymous. Recordings are automatically deleted after 365 days. You can opt-out of Hotjar collecting your information at any time by [_following these instructions_](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).   
  
## Advertising/targeting/remarketing third party cookies

 Cookie name |  Purpose  
---|---  
****Facebook****

_fpb, datr, lu, s, locale, c_user, xs

fr | Used to tailor Facebook advertising to you when you visit their site and for our Facebook advertising campaigns  
**Doubleclick** \- IDE | Used for targeted adverting  
  
Anj

Uuid2 | Used for targeted advertising and to measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns   
  
****LinkedIn****

UserMatchHistory

Bcookie

Lang

Lidc

Visit

_chartbeat2

JSESSIONID

sl 

li_at

BizoID 

| Used for targeted and optimised advertising to distinguish first time users.  
  
**Dotmailer**

DmSessionID

recordID

| These cookies are used to identify when visitors that have been included in an email campaign visit our sites. This helps us to monitor the effectiveness of those campaigns  
  
****Snapchat****

sc_at | Used for targeted adverting   
****Twitter****

Personalization_id

K, js, external referrer

| Allows you to share content via your twitter account and use 'tweet this' buttons  
  
****Youtube****

GPS, YSC, PREF, VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE | Keeps track of your preferences, location, viewing history, when using imbedded Youtube videos  
  
**GetSocial**

_smb_api_session

LSW_WEB

| These cookies enable the usage of GetSocial toolbars for sharing webpages on social networks and is used to track social shares  
  
We know that a lot of visitors to our website use social networking tools, so we have tried to make it easy for you to share our content using these services. We use a button provided by ShareThis to enable this functionality and this button places its own cookies on your machine. We also pull through content from social networks into our own pages, such as embedded Twitter feeds. The social networks, such as Facebook and Twitter, may themselves also put cookies on your machine. We have little control over these 'third party' cookies, so we suggest that you check the respective privacy policies for these external services to help you understand what data these organisations hold about you and what they do with it. For instance, the [Facebook Data Use Policy](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) and the [Twitter privacy policy](https://twitter.com/privacy) give further information about those services.

The following table gives details of some of the third party cookies that can be used and gives links to the appropriate privacy policies for them.

### Legal basis for processing your personal information

Where you provide personal information in order for us to contact you or provide you with optional information, such as subscribing to an electronic newsletter, joining an email mailing list, or subscribing to SMS updates we will be processing your personal data on the basis of your consent.

Where you provide personal information for the purposes of booking or applying for a course, booking onto an event, or making a purchase We will be processing your data for the purposes of administering a contract with you and in order to deliver those services to you.

Where We use your corporate or business contact details to contact you with information We think may be of interest to you We will be processing your data on the basis of legitimate interests, for the performance of our public tasks, or with your consent.

When We use your personal postal mail address or contact telephone number (s) to contact you with information We will be processing your data on the basis of legitimate interests, for the performance of our public tasks, or with your consent.

Where you provide Us with special category (sensitive data) including information on your ethnicity, disability or medical conditions, for example, for the purposes of arranging accessibility or dietary needs, We will be processing your data on the basis of your consent, or for the purposes of equal opportunities monitoring or the performance of statutory duties under the equality act.

Where We use your information to manage our websites and troubleshoot any problems, or to track the effectiveness of our websites and monitor how users interact with them this will be on the basis of our legitimate interests.

Where We are required by law We will process your data on the basis of a legal obligation.

### who we may share your data with

The University will not sell, license or trade your personal information without your consent. We will not share your personal information with others unless they are acting under our instructions or We are required to do so by law.

### retention of your data

We will retain your data for as long as is necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements. Where you have requested to be added to marketing or mailing lists your details will be retained until you choose to unsubscribe to those communications. We may contact you from time to time to check that you are still happy to receive those communications.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, We consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which We process your personal data and whether We can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. 

In some circumstances We may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case We may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

### how we protect your data

Your personal information is stored securely within the University and our staff are trained about the secure handling of personal information. We may also use third party providers to deliver our services, such as externally hosted software or cloud providers. Were we do this, We have measures and terms in place with those providers to ensure that they also protect your data.

### keeping your information up to date

The accuracy of your information is important to us. You can update your information, including your address and contact details, at any time. If you need update the details We hold about you, or believe We hold inaccurate data please contact the relevant department or the Data Protection Officer.

### your rights

Under data protection law you have the right to: 

  * Withdraw your consent where that is the legal basis of our processing
  * Access your personal data that We process
  * Rectify inaccuracies in personal data that We hold about you
  * Be erased, that is your details to be removed from systems that We use to process your personal data
  * Restrict the processing in certain ways
  * Obtain a copy of your data in a commonly used electronic form; and 
  * Object to certain processing of your personal data by us

Please see the ICO website for further information on the above rights:

_[_https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/_](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/)_

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, We may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, We may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

More information on making a request under your rights can be found [_here_](http://www.reading.ac.uk/internal/imps/DataProtection/imps-d-p-datasubjectrights.aspx).

If you would like to exercise your rights, or have any concerns regarding how We have handled your personal information please contact our Data Protection Office at imps@reading.ac.uk

Some rights are dependent on the lawful basis for processing your information. If We have legitimate grounds to not carry out your wishes, these will be explained to you in response to your request.

You also have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner's Office.

### questions about this notice

If there is anything in this notice that you are unclear about, please contact our Data Protection Officer, on the contact details below, who shall be happy to answer any queries you may have concerning this privacy notice or the way in which We process your personal data.

By mail: Information Management and Policy Services, The University of Reading, Whiteknights, PO Box 217, Reading RG6 6AH

By email: _[_imps@reading.ac.uk_](mailto:imps@reading.ac.uk)_

By phone: 0118 378 8981

Complaints can be referred to the Information Commissioners Office, the independent body who oversee Data Protection compliance in the UK.

Email: _[_casework@ico.gsi.gov.uk_](mailto:casework@ico.gsi.gov.uk)_

### changes to this notice

We keep our privacy notice under regular review to ensure best practice and compliance with the law. This privacy notice was last updated on 10/05/2019 

We may change this privacy notice from time to time. If We make significant changes in the way we treat your personal information We will make this clear on [_https://www.reading.ac.uk/_](https://www.reading.ac.uk/) and may also inform you directly. 

### How to contact us

If you have any questions about this notice, our University Data Protection Officer can be contacted at: 

IMPS

University of Reading 

Whiteknights

PO Box 217

Reading

RG6 6AH UK.

Telephone: 0118 378 8981. 

Email: [imps@reading.ac.uk](mailto:imps@reading.ac.uk)
